<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>


<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
    <title type="text">Hugo Theme MemE</title>
    <subtitle type="html">MemE is a powerful and highly customizable GoHugo theme for personal blogs.</subtitle>
    <updated>2021-01-29T11:24:36&#43;08:00</updated>
    <id>https://example.com/</id>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com/" />
    <link rel="self" type="application/atom&#43;xml" href="https://example.com/atom.xml" />
    <author>
            <name>Windson</name>
            <uri>https://example.com/</uri>
            
                <email>wiwindson@outlook.com</email>
            </author>
    <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights>
    <generator uri="https://gohugo.io/" version="0.80.0">Hugo</generator>
        <entry>
            <title type="text">Proportional Pricing Model</title>
            <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://example.com/posts/proportional-pricing-model/" />
            <id>https://example.com/posts/proportional-pricing-model/</id>
            <updated>2021-01-29T11:18:22&#43;08:00</updated>
            <published>2021-01-29T11:00:41&#43;08:00</published>
            <author>
                    <name>Windson</name>
                    <uri>https://io-oi.me/</uri>
                    <email>wiwindson@outlook.com</email>
                    </author>
            <rights>[CC BY-NC-SA 4.0](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc-sa/4.0/deed.en)</rights><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five months ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://osjobs.net/co/&#34;&gt;Overseas Rabbit Course&lt;/a&gt; started using a new pricing model. After applying the new strategy, revenue from each customer has increased by 2000%. According to this data, the new pricing strategy seems to gain great success. Of course, it would be a danger if we simple inferring the reasons for succeeding from numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s like I happened to dig for golden nuggets but thought that I know how to find a gold mine. But after such a large improvement in revenue, I still tend to analyze the reasons behind it.&lt;/p&gt;</summary>
            
                <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Five months ago, &lt;a href=&#34;https://osjobs.net/co/&#34;&gt;Overseas Rabbit Course&lt;/a&gt; started using a new pricing model. After applying the new strategy, revenue from each customer has increased by 2000%. According to this data, the new pricing strategy seems to gain great success. Of course, it would be a danger if we simple inferring the reasons for succeeding from numbers. It&amp;rsquo;s like I happened to dig for golden nuggets but thought that I know how to find a gold mine. But after such a large improvement in revenue, I still tend to analyze the reasons behind it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;previous-pricing-model&#34;&gt;Previous pricing model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseas Rabbit Course is an interview course for programmers including resume review and mock interview services. The previous pricing model is quite straight forward. It started in April 2018, the day Overseas Rabbit went online. Just like other service platforms, our original pricing model charged a uniform price to each customer for the same course. Customers choose the desired course and pay for it, then, we apply the related course for them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/OSJobs/osjobs-info@master/assets/imgs/old%20price.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A common problem for this pricing model is to find the best price, so we adjusted the price in a while. Under the premise that the reduction of price would lead to more customers, we tried different prices to discover the one to achieve profit maximization. However, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t work that well. Looking back, even though this pricing model is used everywhere but may not be the best one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;new-pricing-model&#34;&gt;New pricing model&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Until June 2020, a customer proposed that he would like to use 50% of his monthly salary to pay for our course. It reminds me of another programmer course I have seen before. It is also charged in proportion to the monthly salary. I had doubts about this pricing model at that moment for two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Paying by proportion is much more expensive than a fixed fee. The median salary of Chinese programmers is about 10,000, and 50% of the salary is almost 10 times more than the original fee. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure how many customers are willing to pay such a high amount to participate in the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Job hunting is a combination of luck and ability. Some customers may take a few months to be successfully recruited. Such uncertainty may cause unstable revenue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;However, after we found a customer is willing to pay by proportion. We made some adjustments to the course content and adopted a dynamic charging strategy. Now the course is free to join, and we charge 50% of the customer&amp;rsquo;s salary only when they had been recruitment succeed. I call this pricing strategy &amp;ldquo;Proportional Pricing Model&amp;rdquo;. I believe someone must have discovered it earlier than me and has named it, such as the programmer course I saw before. (Welcome to leave a comment if you found the source. ) Surprisingly, under the new pricing model, there are more customers than before, and we successfully increased our revenue by 20 times recently.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/OSJobs/osjobs-info@master/assets/imgs/new%20price.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;so-why&#34;&gt;So, why&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I suppose there are some potential factors for the increasing revenue:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Consequentialism&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dynamic price&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Willingness of payment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Risk estimation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;consequentialism&#34;&gt;Consequentialism&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the beginning, we thought that customers required to increase the possibility of getting an interview and improve the ability to interview, but we were wrong. &lt;strong&gt;What customers really need is getting a job&lt;/strong&gt;, and there is a huge difference between them. 我从这个策略学到的是，价格本身是微不足道的，关键是客户能够得到什么. Under the previous price model, customers will balance between the course cost and interview skills obtained with their own criterion. On the contrary, under the Proportional Pricing Model, they would balance the course cost with the success of recruitment. So maybe, most people are consequentialists. Then they will only judge the quality of the course based on the actual result after completing the course instead of objectively rate the quality. Proportional Pricing Model closely connects the recruitment certainty with our course.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dynamic-price&#34;&gt;Dynamic price&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proportional Pricing Model means the payment varies with the salary level, customers cannot know the actual number they will pay before getting the job which will make them feel less expensive.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Proportional payment is fairer. Higher cost means a higher salary. Customers should expect to pay as much as possible because it means they have a higher salary.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt; Percentages cannot be directly compared. If setting a fixed fee, such as 6,000 yuan per customer, the customer can directly compare 6,000 yuan with what he/she could purchase, such as books or other courses. &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;willingness-of-payment&#34;&gt;Willingness of payment&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overseas Rabbit offers high-quality courses, but customers don&amp;rsquo;t know it. In this case, the willingness to pay has several related factors:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the quality of our course from customers&amp;rsquo;s view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the demand for the course&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the price of the course.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All the time, we could only try to achieve profit maximization by adjusting the price of the course since it&amp;rsquo;s difficult to control the first two factors. With Proportional Pricing Model, since we only charge after their successful recruitment:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Everyone likes free products, customers can attend courses for free at the beginning. People rarely feel regret for free services.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More than one customer has said that they are willing to spend more than 50% salary to exchange successful recruitment, which has never happened under the previous strategy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;risk-estimation&#34;&gt;Risk estimation&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers may overestimated the risk of not finding a job especially when they didn&amp;rsquo;t have a job.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;other-applications&#34;&gt;Other applications&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;streaming-media-platform-subscription&#34;&gt;Streaming media platform subscription&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;From foreign streaming media platforms, such as Netflix, Youtube, to Chinese platform, such as Tencent Video, Mango TV’s, their utilise a monthly subscription price model. Although they use some strategies to attract customers continuously subscribing, such as 30 days of free trial, continuous monthly discounts, annual discounts, family membership package, there are still several problems:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;it-cost-the-platform-a-lot&#34;&gt;It cost the platform a lot&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually, customers subscribe to the service because of a certain episode, and they will cancel their subscription after watching it (the first-month cancellation rate of streaming media platform is higher than 40%). Therefore, streaming media platforms need to continuously spend money on producing new content or purchasing copyrights, which would bring a lot of costs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;the-customer-is-not-happy&#34;&gt;The customer is not happy&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platforms hope customers could automatically renew, however, no customer will feel that they could take advantage from the same price. People who watch less will regret that they have spent too much on subscription fees. Furthermore, people watch more will not satisfy as well for the following two reasons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Because there are a huge amount of videos, it’s difficult to measure how many videos you need to watch to get the fee back.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mostly, watching videos is just a kind of pastime entertainment. People may feel guilty if they spend too much time on it every month, and it leads to subscription cancellation.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With Proportional Pricing Model, I propose an improved plan:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Customer can join streaming media membership for free, they watch everything from the platform.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only if the customers’s monthly watching time exceeds 20% of the average time among all customers, a monthly fee will be charged&lt;/strong&gt;. For example, Youtube has 10 million members and only 8 million customers will be charged. 2 million customers can enjoy services for free.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The advantages of this scheme are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;fairness&#34;&gt;Fairness&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Charging everyone a fixed price is unfair. Just like electricity bills, charging everyone the same price bill will cause controversy. Therefore, members be charged based on how long they watched is more reasonable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;dynamic-price-1&#34;&gt;Dynamic price&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Customers no longer need to decide whether to subscribe according to a specific episode or auto-renew, because it&amp;rsquo;s free if customers watch less. Since customers are hard to predict whether they have to pay for this month. Their watching time may unconsciously reach the level of charging. As a result, they enjoyed the service and are also willing to pay.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;willingness-to-pay&#34;&gt;Willingness to pay&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everyone likes free products. If the streaming media platforms adopt the strategy I said, I will subscribe to all streaming media platforms without hesitation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;its-fun&#34;&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s Fun&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s quite interesting to guess whether you need to pay this month. If people don&amp;rsquo;t have to pay for this month, people would feel like they earned money.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4 id=&#34;operating-cost&#34;&gt;Operating cost&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Platforms could adjust payment proportion to manage costs and profits.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;Summary&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It also reminds me of some other examples. gyms could charge according to customers&#39; weight loss, and amusement parks could charge according to how many facilities you played. I believe that &amp;ldquo;Proportional Pricing Model&amp;rdquo; can be applied to different industries to create more revenue. When I was reading books related to the economy, they rarely talk about pricing model. In our case, the problem is our pricing model and now we fixed it.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
            
            
            
            
            
                
                    
                
                    
                
            
        </entry>
    
</feed>
